<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>


		<item>
			<title>art update</title>
			<link>https://youtherthyf.whf.bz/art-gallery.html</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
				<img src="./images/non-digital/bootloop.png">
						<img src="./images/digital/danteog.png">
						<p>لعبة 'موت لاليتش' اخيرا نزلت الديمو. كنت مدمنها علي نيوجراوندز و شكلي هدمنها تاني. الشخصية الجديدة دانتي شكله مسلي</p>
						<img src="./images/digital/dante.png">
							<p>لسة مش بحب تلوين رسماتي اوي بس حاسس إنه بالطبقات الصح اقدر اعمل حاجة ترضيني</p>
						<img src=".images/sketches/bird-study.png">
						<img src=".images/sketches/bird-study2.png">
								<p>تدريب في رسم الكروان</p>
								<img src=".images/sketches/sawsaw-referencesheet.png">
									<p>تصميم اولي لشخصية لمشروع التخرج بتاعي</p>
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 aug 2025 15:13:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>bootloop-fanart</title>
			<link>https://youtherthyf.whf.bz/art-gallery.html</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
				<img src="./images/non-digital/bootloop.png">
				<img src="./images/non-digital/bootloop-sketch.png">
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 aug 2025 15:13:00</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>سكتشات لشغل الجامعة</title>
			<link></link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
				<img src="./images/sketches/fmttm-sketch1.jpeg">
					<img src="./images/sketches/fmttm-sketch2.jpeg">
							شغل جامعة. مطلوب مننا بوستر لاغنية fly me to the moon بتاعت فرانك ساناترا
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>fri, 22 aug 2025 03:25:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>new panty and stockings</title>
			<link></link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<img src="./images/digital/gunsmith bitch.png">
					<img src="./images/sketches/WhatsApp Image 2025-08-22 at 2.42.51 AM.jpeg">
					<p>شخبطة لبانتي و ستوكمج. الموسم الجديد حلو, الوييب الأشقر مزعج, بس غير كده كل الشخصيات التنين عجبني</p>
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>fri, 22 aug 2025 03:25:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>

			<title>new RSS.. again</title>
			<link>https://youtherthyf.whf.bz/newrss.xml</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
				<p>تلقيم جديد.. عشان انا نقلت لإستضافة تانية</p>
				<p>new RSSfeed.. sense i moved to another webhost</p>
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 04:40:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<title>إذاعة يوزرسيف المصرية</title>
		<link>https://youtherthyf-madehouse.neocities.org/</link>
		<description>
			personal ramblings and drawings
		</description>
		<image>
			<url>https://youtherthyf-madehouse.neocities.org/images/favicon.ico</url>
		</image>

		<item>
			<title>salon update</title>
			<link>https://youtherthyf-madehouse.neocities.org/art-gallery</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
				<img src="./images/non-digital/samerexci2.jpeg">
					<p>تمرين رسم كوميكس</p>
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 July 2025 16:40:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>salon update</title>
			<link>https://youtherthyf-madehouse.neocities.org/art-gallery</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
				<img src="./images/sketches/samirex.jpeg">
					<p>تمرين علي طريقة الرسم بتاعت مجلة سمير</p>
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 July 2025 16:40:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>PC98 style pixel art in blender compositor</title>
			<link>https://youtherthyf-madehouse.neocities.org/blogs/pc98-composite</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<p>date:thu 2025-07-03</p>

	  <p>this blog was supposed to come out <b>MONTHS AGO</b> but between college, computer reformatting, recreating this file, college again, ect. ect. this ended up thrown to the side. but i felt i should finish this before moving to write anything else...</p>

	  <p>i don't hide my preference for old PC games and old tech generally, especially 90s and 80s era computers, and well over a few months ago i learned of the PC9800, a japanese computer created by NEC targeted at businesses, with a special chip for rendering kanjis. that, along with being an open platform, made it a perfect platform for visual novel games. i was fascinated by the style that developed in these games, a mix of anime and pixel art. especially after stumbling onto <a href="https://jordanislame.neocities.org/pages/individual%20shrines/pc98shrine">this PC98 shrine</a>, which ultimately spiraled into me making this project to see if i can recreate it in blender's compositor.
		</p>

		<h2>enough ramblings</h2>

		<p>for the main dither i used <a href="https://medium.com/@pangkhangee/pixel-perfect-dithering-shader-in-blender-fd6898e8ba23">this medium article as base</a>, except there were a problem as that node setup relies on vectors and texture coordinates to generate the pattern, neither of which exist in the compositor, so i needed alternatives or recreations.</p>
		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/1111.png">
			
		<p>the point of the texture coordinates was to get a horizontal and a vertical gradient to use for creating the pixels. they can be easily replaced with 2 blend textures with the orientations needed. now we multiply each texture by a specific value that will determine the size of our pixels(more on it in a bit), preferably you want to add a value node to make sure they both have the same value(although stretched pixels could look interesting if you wanted that), followed by a floor that will give us a clean pixel.</p>
		
		<h2>shading patterns</h2>
		<p>in pixel art it is common to represent different shades through different dithering patterns, numbered from darkest to lightest.</p>
		<ul>
			<li>pattern 1: insert each texture into a floored modula with a value of 2, then multiply them by each other.</li>
			<li>pattern 5: take the output of pattern 1 and inverse it by subtracting it by 1. this creates a problem that will be addressed in a bit</li>
			<li>patterns 4: create both an add and a substract and plug both textures into them. put the output of the add into a calmped floored modula with a value of 4, and put the output of the subtract into a clamped wrap with a max of 4 and a min of 0. finally multiply the outputs of the floored modulo and the wrap together.</li>
			<li>pattern 2: take the output of pattern 4 and inverse it by subtracting it by 1. same problem mentioned with pattern 5, again will be addressed shortly.</li>
			<li>pattern 3: add the two textures together, then blug the result into a floor modulo with a value of 2</li>
		</ul>

		<h2>about the problem</h2>
		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/excolor.png">
		<p>patterns 2 and 5 are negative versions of patterns 4 and 1 respectively, created by taking the original pattern and subtracting it by 1, creating a negative value. this is fine for a shader, but in the composite this results in inverted colors(shown above). the best solution i found for this was to multiply(clamped) patterns 2 and 5 by -1, which solved the problem.</p>

		<h2>shading data</h2>
		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/exshad.png">
		<p>now we will get the shading data then separate them to choose where each pattern of dither will appear. personally i use cycles(low pass number) with the denoising data, diffuse direct, diffuse color, and ambient occlusion(AO) passes turned on in the view layer.</p>
		<p>now multiply the diffuse direct and AO passes and insert the output into a denoise node, with the denoise normal and albino inserted. i personally find fast prefilter and follow scene quality to be good enough, but this might be up to you. </p>
		<p>insert the denoise output into a pixelate node, the reason and value will be explained in a bit, for now we will leave it at 1. finally multiply this value by the number of shades we will have, here we have pure bright, 5 dither patterns, and pure dark, making 7 in total. so we will set the multiply to 7</p>
		<h2>separating shades</h2>
		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/excolor sep.png">
		<p>for separation, a few compare nodes will do the job, one for each degree of shade. the exact values for the epsilon, what determines where our  of the compares will depend on your preference and scene, but i personally went with the following:</p>
		<ol>
			<li>0.5</li>
			<li>0.7</li>
			<li>0.9</li>
			<li>1.1</li>
			<li>1.3</li>
			<li>1.5</li>
			<li>82.4(you can put whatever big number here it doesn't matter</li>
		</ol>
		<p>then we subtract each compare from the one below it(example: compare[2]-compare[1], i.e compare[2] is in the top socket, while compare[1] is below) to get specific zones we can apply the patterns to, which we do by multiplying each of the patterns with it's respective subtract in order, except the last one.</p>
		<p>finally add all the multiply nodes' outputs, along with the final subtract, to generate a hashed tone map.(shown below)</p>

		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/2025-07-03_09-26.png">
		<p>now we take the tone map we created and use it to change colors. i personally used it as the factor of a mix node, with the two values being the diffuse color pass, and a version of it multiplied by a light purple, although using it as the fact of a color correct node also yielded nice results.</p>

		<h2>keeping the pixels sharp</h2>
		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/2025-07-03_09-36.png">
		<p>you might have noticed a problem while making this, that being the pixels getting cut off. this is because the original shading data isn't pixelated, they are normal smooth gradients, so when we create the sections they don't follow any squared grid and transition from one pattern to another mid pixel.</p>
		<p>this problem is where the pixelation node's role shows up. the pixelation, if set to the right value, will force the shading data to follow a squared grid and solve our problem.</p>
		<p>the exact value of the pixelation requires a little math, it should be your render resolution/scale of the blend textures created at the start. example: my render is 600x600px, and i set my scale to 100, so the pixelation should be 6.</p>
		
		<h2>highlights</h2>
		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/2025-07-03_09-51.png">
		<p>highlights are the exact same as shadows, except with way higher values. i choose the values:</p>
		<ol>
			<li>5.6</li>
			<li>5.8</li>
			<li>6.0</li>
			<li>6.2</li>
			<li>6.4</li>
			<li>6.6</li>
			<li>61.7(again, you can put whatever big number here it doesn't matter</li>
		</ol>
		<p>then use this output as factor for mixing the shaded image with any colors you choose the highlights to be, i went with a light beige.</p>
		<h2>Line art</h2>
		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/2025-07-03_10-00.png">
		<p>for line art i used a baked line art object, placed on it's own view layer following <a href="https://blender.stackexchange.com/questions/282768/grease-pencil-line-art-layer-how-to-place-it-into-a-render-pass-view-layer">this guide</a>, creating the exact line art we need.</p>
		<p>then insert that layer's render pass into a pixelation node, making sure the pixelation's value is correct as explained above, then put it's output through an alpha over node and a clamped floor node. sense the line art's layer has a transparent background, the pixelations creates semi transparent pixels which we don't want, the alpha over and floor nodes prevent this.</p>
		<p>finally use the output of the floor node as the factor to mix your rendered scene, and the color you want your lineart to be, i choose black.</p>


		<h2>Final thoughts</h2>
		<img src="./blog-images/pc98/futaba.gif">
		<p>the example above was rendered without highlights, as i personally find them ugly</p>
		<p>this setup is by no means perfect, as non square resolutions result in the pixels getting stretched, i have tried experimenting with giving each texture it's own scale but haven't had much success. i am very open for suggestions on how to fix this problem</p>
		<p>i want to automate the calculation of the pixelation nodes, but i am not that familiar with drivers so it is outside of my skill set.</p>
		<p>i feel the textures are missing up the vibes(this is the in game <a href="https://www.models-resource.com/playstation_3/persona5/model/65810/">futaba model</a>. thanks VGresource i love you), probably should have lowered their resolution in krita before .. maybe next time.</p>
		<p>i am hungry</p>
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 3 July 2025 10:58:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>محمود صلاح</title>
			<link>https://youtherthyf-madehouse.neocities.org/art-gallery</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
				<img src="https://youtherthyf-madehouse.neocities.org/images/non-digital/mahmoudsalah.jpeg">
					<p>إهداءلأراجوزي المفضل الجديد, محمود صلاح. الحتي في الحقائق البصيطة, زي تجسس الشركات, لازم, كتر خيره, يرفه عننا. متقلقش عزيزي القارئ الاجهزة مش محتاجة تقري إشارات مخك, الخشرمية مكروفون و جهاز متصل بالشبكة تاعتك عامله الواجب كتر خيرها</p>
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 04:40:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>noggi's video</title>
			<link>https://youtherthyf-madehouse.neocities.org/blogs/noggi-arcane</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					<div class="text-container">
      <h1>Noggi's arcane video and it's consequences</h1>
      <p>date:tue 2025-01-14</p>
      <p>a while back, maybe a week ago, i watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aj4_VLZM_GA" target="_blank">a video by Noggi </a> where he tried to recreate a scene from arcane using blender(mostly). it has inspired me to rework my workflow to build more of the shading in the compositore rather than the render engine it's self.</p>
      <p>using my short shezmu animation from my maya class as a lab rat i started missing around with differet data passes. i also switched from Eevee to cycles to allow me access to more passes. with a low enough sample rate it takes around the same time to render</p>
      <p>the original</p>
      <img src="./blog images/2025-01-14_08-15.png" alt="" style="width:300px;">
      <p>the done through compostion</p>
      <img src="./blog images/2025-01-14_08-26.png" alt="" style="width:300px;">
      <p>normally i get the cellshading from a shader node group, the basic shader to RGB into a color-ramp setup you are familiar with from every youtube tutorial except for slightly changing the tent of the shaded area or adding a texture. but here i used a normal psdf shader and did all the cellshading and color shifts in in the compositor. the advantages of this is being able to apply it to all objects in the scene at once without needing to edit all their shaders. and in case i need a specific object or part to be shaded differently i could use an object index or a mask</p>
      <img src="./blog images/2025-01-14_08-38.png" alt="" style="width:500px;">
      <p>as noggi explains, much better than i can, this allows me full creative freedom over the look and style. compisiting is already a must for good renders but working on passes sepratly(a flat color pass, a lighting pass, ect.) then combining them into a final render, rather than simply working on a combined image pass, allows for lighting and coloring to be edited freely.</p>
      <p>want to remove shadows from or add them to specific parts? mask it</p>
      <p>shading looks good on all objects except one? correct the colors on that one object instead of having to edit the material and re-render it</p>
      <p>am still new to this workflow, and masks in general, but i can aleady see it's potencial</p>
      <p>we will see where this goes. anyways i haven't had a proper lunch in days, no reason i just forget to eat sometimes, steak and peas anyone?</p>
    </div>
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 04:40:00</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>first</title>
			<link></link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
					]]>
			</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 04:40:00</pubDate>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
